SAMAN OTHMAN

PROCUREMENT OFFICER ERBIL, IRAQ

Mob:

+9647501705244

+9647510017606

Email: Saman.husman@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Saman Othman

SUMMARY

Highly experienced procurement officer with nearly 3 years of experience in executive planning and production, Skilled in Logistic Support, Strong purchasing professional with bachelor of English Language. Dedicated and committed to growing and expanding businesses.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROCUREMENT OFFICER

TREVI GROUP,, MOSUL DAM PROJECT

May 2017 - Current

- Develop and review purchase requests and insure authorization as necessary to facilitate the timely purchase of new products. Studying sales records and inventory needs.
- · Negotiate pricing and purchase goods and ensure delivery in a timely manner.
- Administrating an internal purchasing system and create a successful procurement process.
- Structuring product contracts, coordinate with suppliers and placing orders.
- Create forecast of demand to be prepared for upcoming requirements.
- Review delivery orders to ensure supply is met, taking availability, cost, manufacturing process, and lead times into consideration.

PROCUREMENT ASSISSTANT

TREVI GROUP, MOSUL DAM PROJECT

Oct 2016 - Apr 2017

- Provided assistance to procurement officer in all aspects.
- Gathered information and created reports from all departments.
- Presented reports to the procurement officer, relaying information from department heads accurately.
- Communicated information from the procurement officer to the rest of the management team.

TRANSLATOR

AKADEMI LEGAL TRANSLATION, ERBIL

Aug 2014 - Aug 2015

- Check original texts to ensure that translations retain the content, meaning, and feeling of the original material.
- Check translations of technical terms of terminology to ensure that they are accurate and remain consistent throughout translation revisions.
- · Proofread, edit, and revise translated materials.
- · Provide translation services from English to Arabic and Kurdish language vice versa.

EDUCATION AND SKILLS

SALAHADDIN UNIVERSITY

College of Languages - English Department, ERBIL 2012 - 2016

- IT Skills: Microsoft Office, Editing, Internet and social media.(Intermediate Level)
- English Language: Speaking and Listening (Advanced Level)
- Arabic Langauge: Speaking and Listening (Intermediate Level)
- Persian Language: Speaking and Listening (Advanced Level)
- Kurdish Language: Mother Tongue

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Experienced presenter, public speaker, organizing and management skills, the ability to withstand the pressures of work, the ability to work within a group, Willingness to travel in and out of the field, Excellent diplomatic and communication skills.

References are available upon request